Believe all ogre again.
Shrek the Musical is a music, comedy, fantasy film
directed by Michael John Warren.
Put out of his swamp solitude by a wicked tyrant's order, grumpy ogre Shrek goes on a journey – accompanied by a
chatterbox donkey – to retrieve a beautiful princess from a tower, unaware that she has secrets all her own.
Shrek, played by Brian d'Arcy James.
Fiona, played by Sutton Foster.
Donkey, played by Daniel Breaker.
Lord Farquaad, played by Christopher Sieber.
Pinocchio / Magic Mirror, played by John Tartaglia.
Sugar Plum Fairy / Gingy / Dragonette, played by Haven Burton Paschall.
Shrek the Musical is a musical with music by Jeanine Tesori
and book and lyrics by David Lindsay-Abaire.
It is based on the 2001 DreamWorks Animation film Shrek, along with elements of its
sequels: Shrek 2, Shrek Forever After and William Steig's 1990 book Shrek!.
After a trial run in Seattle, the original Broadway production opened in December
2008 and closed after a run of over 12 months in January 2010.
It was followed by a tour of the United States which opened in 2010, and a
re-vamped West End production from June 2011 to February 2013.
A high definition filming of the Broadway production, shot by RadicalMedia, was released on DVD, Blu-ray, and
digital download on October 15, 2013, in North America and December 2, 2013, in the United Kingdom.
The digital version of the film was made available on
Netflix beginning in December 2013.
The film explores themes of friendship, wolf, donkey, feminism, swamp.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.